Inventory of the Al Christie Papers, 1913-1974 (Bulk 1916-1937)
University of Wyoming. American Heritage Center.
Al Christie papers
1913-1974 (bulk 1916-1937)
Christie, Al, 1886-1951
05334
4.88 cubic ft. (11 boxes)
University of Wyoming. American Heritage Center.
Production files and publicity materials primarily for Christie Film Company silent films.
Biography of Al Christie
Al Christie started working for the Nestor Film Company in 1909. Nestor was based in New Jersey, but in 1911 Christie moved to California to open a studio for Nestor on the west coast. This was the first movie studio in Hollywood. Al Christie founded Christie Film Company with his brother Charles Christie in 1916. The company was best known for producing Christie Comedies. Many of these productions were two-reel shorts, but the company also produced full-length features. Christie Film Company ceased production in 1933.
Scope and Content
The collection contains scripts, story outlines, publicity materials and synopses. The scripts include "Divorce Made Easy", "Charley's Aunt", "College Cuties", "Loose Relations", and others. Also included are photographs of actors (including Dorothy Devore) and stills from movies, (including "The Nervous Wreck"). In addition there is a scrapbook of publicity for Betty Compson, a Christie Comedy star.
Access Restrictions
There are no access restrictions on the materials for research purposes, and the collection is open to the public.
Related Materials
There are no known other archival collections created by Al Christie at the date of processing.
Acquisition Information
This material was received from Dorothy Devore in 1974-1976.
Existence and Location of Copies
Digital reproductions of select portions of this collection are available at: http://digitalcollections.uwyo.edu:8180/luna/servlet/uwydbuwy~88~88.
Access Terms
Compson, Betty, 1897-1974; Christie, Charles; Devore, Dorothy, 1899-1976; Christie Film Company; Silent films --United States; Motion pictures -- United States; Motion pictures -- Production and direction -- United States;; Scripts
Arts, Humanities, and Social Sciences; Performing Arts
Container List
- Series I. Production Files
  - Manuscripts, undated (Box 1)
  - Story Outlines, undated (Box 1)
  - Scripts - Motion Picture, circa 1913-1937 (Box 2-8)
  - Scripts - Play, 1922, undated (Box 8)
  - Scripts - Radio, undated (Box 8)
  - Story Outlines, 1920-1926, undated (Box 9)
  - Synopses, 1926-1934, undated (Box 9)
  - Miscellaneous, 1927-1931, undated (Box 9)
- Series II. Publicity Files
  - Biographical Information - Al Christie, undated (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Biographical Information - Betty Compson, 1974 (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Biographical Information - Betty Compson (Scrapbook), 1914-1971 (Box 11)
  - Newspaper Clippings - "A Corner in Hollywood", 1927 (Box 1)
  - Photographs - Al Christie, 1917, undated (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Photographs - Betty Compson, 1916, undated (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Photographs - Dorothy Devore, 1923-1924 (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Photographs - Lee Moran, 1913, undated (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Photographs - The Nervous Wreck (publicity stills), 1926 (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - Photographs - The Nervous Wreck (publicity stills) - Phyllis Haver, 1926 (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - Photographs - The Nervous Wreck (publicity stills) - Vera Steadman, 1926 (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - Photographs - The Nervous Wreck (publicity stills) - Mack Swain, 1926 (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - Photographs - Miscellaneous Publicity Stills, undated (Box 10, Folder 11-13)
  - Photographs - Billie Rhodes, 1915-1966 (Box 10, Folder 14)
  - Publicity Releases, undated (Box 2)
  - Reviews - College Cuties; Sweethearts on Parade, 1930 (Box 2)
  - Reviews - Charley's Aunt, 1930-1931 (Box 2)
  - Miscellaneous, 1922-1924, undated (Box 9)